Hello everyone. Welcome back to another
episode of NFA Live. It is great to see
you. Uh I am joined by uh the wonderful
Mr. Ben Cowan. Hello Ben.
>> How's it going?
>> Very well, thanks. And Mr. Rob Wolf.
Hello Rob.
>> Hello. Thanks for having me.
>> Thank you for joining. Thank you for
joining. It's great to see you
gentlemen. Um another another
interesting week in crypto. Um there's
the token we're sort we appear to be
deep in conference season at the moment.
>> Um the token 2049 conference happening
in Singapore and all the other sort of
along that. So there's quite a lot of
excitement there. Um but market the
crypto market's struggling a bit even
while uh stocks continue to print new
highs which is I don't know either a
little concerning or well good news if
you're in stocks I suppose. So, uh,
folks, everyone watching, if you're not
already subscribed to Ben and Rob, then
what are you doing? You need to rethink
your life choices urgently. Uh, there
are links below where you can follow
them. We, uh, we won't hold it against
you if now is your first time. Um, and,
uh, yeah, the way it's going to work
today is uh, I'm going to ask uh, Ben
and Rob their opinion on a few pressing
issues in crypto and otherwise. Um, and
then if we have time at the end, we will
take some audience questions as well.
So, if you have any questions, please do
leave them in the comments and um we
will try and get to those when we get to
them. But, uh I would like to start um
by asking Ben, Rob, I know um I know
given the chance you can rattle on about
bonds for, you know, anything between
>> three and six hours at a time. So, I I
won't ask this of you, Rob, but Ben, um
I do want to ask about the bond yield
situation. uh the situation in the bond
market at the moment that yields have
actually eased off a little bit in the
last 24 hours or so. But um one of the
themes of uh the last few months has
been bond yields just grinding higher
and higher. And I should point out that
that's not just in the United States but
across many other countries as well. But
obviously uh US bond yields um are the
ones that kind of make the headlines
because they basically set uh set the
rate for pretty much everyone else. So
with that in mind, with bond yields sort
of grinding ever higher, how do you how
do you think this could end? Ben, what
do you think this looks like? Because as
you know, as you've said, this is one of
the reasons why really markets
everywhere, risk assets especially,
should be struggling. Um, and yet as I
just said, you know, stocks are at
all-time highs. So, how do you think
this plays out? Do you think there's any
way to get yields down in a sort of
sustainable way, or is this just
something we need to get used to now?
>> I think it ends. I I think there will be
a local top in yields at least. Uh, that
probably will last for a while. Like, if
you guys remember, we had one in 2023
that lasted for three years. Um, I think
we're about to have another one here
really, really soon. And my guess is
that it happens
before or around the midterms. I I think
that's going to be around peak fear on
rates for a while. And I think one of
the reasons you're seeing yield surge
right now is because the Fed w the Fed
was originally looking to raise rates in
October, at least according to the
markets, right? like the markets thought
the Fed was going to raise rates in
October and then following the soft PCE
report and the soft labor market report.
Uh it it has kind of allowed the Fed to
to back off and and kind of take a
slower approach here, but I don't really
think the market necessarily buys the
soft PCE report. Like PCE is still going
up and the reason it came in soft was
because they revised how it was
calculated. um which again is is kind of
an irritating thing that that they do
and this is not the first time that
they've done it. I mean even the way
they calculate inflation is different
than it used to be in the 1970s. Um so I
I think that the market that the bond
vigilantes are just you know they've
been revoling because we probably they
were the 2-year yield is at like 4.8
4.9% meaning we're probably not really
at in restrictive territory right now as
far as monetary policy goes. And so I'm
thinking maybe right around the next
FOMC is going to be around like peak
fear. A lot of times what happens like
if you look at 2022 and 2018, what
happens is that yields will top sometime
in October and then they'll they'll kind
of go back up around the midterms and
then fall down right after right after
the midterms. So that is that's my guess
as to what's going to happen. And as far
as the markets, normally commodities
like gold and silver, they go down when
rates are going up, right? When the
dollar is going up, when rates are going
up, metals go down. And that's what
they've been doing. But what you look
for to get the sign that rates are
topping is watch for metals to bottom
because normally metals bottom
at or before yields top and they start
showing strength. And then normally risk
assets uh like crypto don't really start
showing that that real weakness until
after rates have topped and started
coming back down. So it it's a little
counterintuitive, right? Like you would
think that raising rate like rising long
end would would take um risk assets down
with it and that is sometimes true in
certain regimes like that was true in
2023 but in 2026 it's actually been the
opposite, right? I mean, every every one
of Bitcoin's lows this year actually
occurred while the 10-year was going
down. And while the 10-year was going
up, Bitcoin was actually also going up.
Uh, so I and I think the reason if if
you had to come up with a reason for
that, I think it's because as the long
end goes up,
>> perhaps it just means, you know, things
are fine, right? Like the economy is
fine, rates are going higher, the
economy can handle it. And when the
rates are going down, it's more so
because there's like a like a growth
scare or like why are rates going down?
So, I think that's what we're looking
at. And I would expect I would expect
the the long end to top probably within
the next month or so, which means that
things like, you know, things like
bonds, uh I know people have talked a
lot about TLT, that stuff in my opinion
will is looking to put in a low uh very
very soon.
>> Okay. Okay. Very interesting. Yeah. And
I guess I guess the midterms as well are
a real factor given that there's so much
uncertainty around them and you know
what what Trump and and the
administration in general might do in
the leadup to them, what they might do
actually after them and that's you know
that's quite aside from what the result
might be. I mean I know you know a lot
of people seem to think the Democrats
will will sweep it but we just don't
know do we? So yeah, that that
uncertainty as you say is probably
feeding into that whole yield equation.
So perhaps that will that will unwind a
bit once we actually know who's who
controls Congress and Yeah.
>> Right.
>> Interesting.
>> Okay. Thanks, Ben. Um so, uh I want to
move I want to change gear a little bit
and ask about uh talk a little bit about
social media and how it affects us. This
is something that gets gets talked about
a lot, but it's something I I wanted to
get your opinions on as fellow content
creators as much as anything else. So,
are social media algorithms making us
too doomer? Um, and you know, by that I
mean like, you know, are we just
inclined to um, you know, to make
content and view content that says, "Oh,
everything's going to be, you know,
everything's going down the toilet.
Everything's everything's societyy's
going to collapse. we're all going to be
poor and dead and enslaved by AI within
three years or whatever it is. Um, you
know, is that the case? And and and on
the flip side of that, you know, when
you consider all the advances that are
actually being made in in in technology,
you know, in things like biotechnology,
AI, all these sort of things, should we
not perhaps be a little bit more
optimistic about the future? Um, Rob,
can I start with you on this one? What
what do you make of it? Are we too
doomer?
>> ATMs.
So, what I'm talking about here is this
doomerism that we see it everywhere.
It's because whatever we click on and
whatever we view on, you're going to get
more of that stuff. That's just how
Facebook works. That's where how YouTube
works, how X works. So, if you have a
slight inclination for dumerism, you're
going to get that 247 365.
>> That's pretty much how it all works.
>> But I've been around a long time. I'm
old and uh everything hurts. But I will
say this that I was around before the
internet. I was around before the
computers. And if you had a computer in
your house back when I was growing up,
I'm like, "What are you, a millionaire?"
That's crazy. But it really comes down
to, like I said, ATMs. Do me a favor.
Can you share this screen?
>> Yes. Let me add that. There we are. So
back in the 70s, we were supposed to
lose a ton of jobs and it was because of
technology that was that was coming
forth and that was ATMs. No one really
seen it because before that you had to
go to a bank branch to get your actual
money and you can actually pull money
out without them giving you too much of
a hard time because they used to do it
all the time. So in 1970 as far as jobs
go there was 300,000 tellers. That's a
lot. And they thought when the ATMs came
out around 1972, 1968, somewhere around
there, they thought that it would start
to go down, but the exact opposite
happened in 2010, you had 600,000 ATMs,
uh, 400,000 ATMs installed, and he had
600,000 tellers. So, what happened? It's
because there was three things that
happened. First of all, became cheaper.
ATMs cut the staff, which people are
like, well, Rob, that's what it is. To
cut staff, you lost jobs. But the thing
that was most important was this. There
was cheaper branches to make. That's why
you see all these different bank
branches from everywhere and they're in
your community. And it became better
because tellers, they had to stop
counting cash and started helping
people. Here's the thing about your your
branch location. It's not just a branch
location. It's a sales pitch. When you
go in, I need some money. Oh, you Well,
here you go, Mr. Wolf. Right here. And
here's the money that you request for
helping anything out with maybe like a a
loan or a credit card or any kind of
like a savings account. They'll come in.
You know what? Maybe I need that. And
before you know it, you're sucked into
the banking. And that's the great thing
about having these new branches because
that helped out the banks a tremendous
amount. It's a lot better to have it
down the street than going 10 20 miles
to your local branch. So that actually
worked out pretty well for uh ATMs and
jobs. So remember this as far as like
doomerism go because we're going to see
a lot of that with with AI coming out
and of course we're going to talk about
you know this new quantum and and of
course a new algorithm that could
potentially break Bitcoin. Tech replaces
tasks and it creates more jobs. So AI to
me is the next ATM. So think of it this
way. I think of it like this. In Puerto
Rico, we have a big brain drain. A lot
of the doctors, the lawyers, a lot of
these people, they go to the mainland.
So we don't have as many doctors and
lawyers are supposed to have here. So
wouldn't it be great if they could say,
you know what, we're going to cut we're
with AI, we're going to have the ability
to cut to make a new branch in half or a
third or a quarter. And then you could
have one doctor service many branches
because it takes a lot less time and a
lot le less effort. That's the beauty of
where we could go with with AI. So I
know people will say, "Well, that's
doomerism and that's pretty much it."
But I think that you're going to see the
ones that embrace it, especially the
corporations, the the corporations that
are firing their people right now are
going to regret it because all they had
to do was train their employees to 10x.
Instead of being the status quo, they
could have 10xed their company and I
think they screwed up. So there's that
part. So, don't feel too bad. And then,
real quickly, I know you guys uh I don't
want to drown out, but it comes down to
this. It's tech and regulation equals
boom. Because there's one thing that
people when I was researching this, a
lot of people forgot about this. I
didn't even know. In 1994, what
accelerated the whole thing with with
ATMs and bank branches? In 1994, there
was a law that was passed, the Regal
Neil Act. So, you had the tech of ATMs,
which reduced the amount of people. You
had the act that came in and what it
allowed people allowed branches to do is
to to move and to uh make new branches
everywhere they wanted to go. And
because of that, because of those two
factors, you had a big boom. So,
wouldn't it be great? We've got a great
technology in crypto. We got stable
coins that can really do payments. We
can do real world tokenization, real
world assets. If we would just have
regulation to either get the hell out of
the way or give us some clarity, which
got bombed out, imagine how much further
we would be. and Europe is going to pay
the price of that. I know you guys cover
that over in Coinb. So, when I take a
look at this, I just think of ATMs.
>> Yeah, that's a really interesting
analogy because Yeah, I it's ATMs are
just something I mean, now they're kind
of they're in in a lot of places,
certainly in the UK and and here in the
UAE, like they're, you know, you don't
see nearly as many of them because fewer
and fewer people seem to be using cash.
But then yeah, you can see how they
actually they actually contribute
probably contributed a huge amount to
economic growth because I guess it made
it easy for people to get their money
and then go and spend it in the economy,
you know. So like you didn't have to you
didn't have to walk to your you know
drive I suppose if you're in the US you
drive everywhere, don't you? But drive
to your local branch um to you know to
during opening hours. It it just opened
up so much more and thus so much more
growth.
>> Yeah. And one last thing I'll say is I
know people will say, "But, you know,
technology will wipe out some jobs." And
you're right. Uh I don't need a
typewriter repairman. It just doesn't
exist anymore. So again, the ones that
embrace the new tech are the ones that
going to work out. The ones that don't,
I think, are going to be swept up by the
ones that do.
>> Yeah. Well, that's that's fascinating.
and and we're going to come we're going
to sort of revisit this in a minute when
uh when we talk more a little bit more
about AI but um yeah that that's
fascinating analogy as I say Rob thanks
for that um Ben same question to you are
we are we sort of pandering to the kind
of to the to the dumerish dumerishness
of social media algorithms should we be
a bit more optimistic about things
>> I mean I also was thinking about ATMs so
Rob
>> you're welcome
be honest with the with the two with the
two biggest ATM shills in in America.
>> Um
yeah, I mean I think it's good. I mean,
so you know, I a while back I was uh
like on on Twitter, I remember just it's
so easy to find yourself in an echo
chamber, you know, whether it's whatever
whatever it is. And I remember going out
and like specifically following like 20
or 30 accounts that just had completely
different views than than me about
things. And I'm not I'm not just talking
about about markets, you know, talking
about like everything. And the point
was, you know, like I I wanted to to not
be in an echo chamber cuz sometimes it
it feels like we live in one when, you
know, we're we're we talk with each
other and then we're surrounded by
people that care about the same things,
but then I go out into the real world
and like no one cares about like 99% of
the stuff that I even care about, you
know? Like I like sometimes I'm like
walking at the grocery store and I'm
like, man, that person has no idea what
the price of Bitcoin is by this second.
They have no idea what the 10-year yield
is. They have no idea where the dollar
is trading. And I'm like I'm kind of
envious of them, you know, like like I
don't I don't think of myself as better.
I'm just like, man, that'd be that'd be
kind of a nice life to not have to to
think about all that stuff. Um, so I I
would say, yeah, like I think it's good
to to kind of
expand out a bit and and and sort of
challenge our own own opinions because
and I and I've seen it happen with
everyone. Like everyone has their own
little bubble that they're in. And it's
funny because there's all these like um
like micro influencers and like every
category and like everyone has these
like super loyal dedicated follower uh
follower base and like some of the most
niche things you could ever even
imagine. within that category. And then
if you meet those those those fans in
real life, they're like, "Wait, you
don't know who this is. You don't know
who that is." But it's like, "No, I
don't care about that stuff." But it it
is I think it's a good thing to to kind
of expand out and and um not not just
sit in the the the Doom Echo chamber.
For sure.
>> Yeah. Yes. What a thing to be walking
past someone and think think they've
they've no idea Zcash has pumped so
much.
They have no idea that despite the fact
that all these things have pumped so
much, they're still down 80% against
Bitcoin over the last 10 years
>> and yet they're still buying eggs in a
grocery store. They don't know that
their financial future is at risk. Yeah,
exactly.
>> I think someone in the someone in the
comments said, "I ignorance is bliss."
And I could not agree more. It is uh
Yeah, it
um yeah, very true. Very true. like
everyone is inside their own echo
chamber and um you know I would say from
the point of view of a of a content
creator as well you know the stuff that
we do on coin bureau we we we often feel
like we're kind of stuck in this sort of
doom loop because we you know we have we
have weekly meetings about what content
we're going to do you know what we're
going to look at what we're going to
cover on uh each one of our 565 channels
and um you know like quite often we have
this discussion where it's like can we
find some, you know, what what what's
the good news happening out there at the
moment? Like what's, you know, what's
going really well or something like
that. And quite a lot of the time it's
like, yeah, that would be a really
interesting thing to cover, but no one
will watch it.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, no one cares. And I we have we
have tried this with sort of videos in
the past, you know, the occasional the
occasional one that sort of tries to be
a bit more like positive, you know, a
good news story. I remember insisting
that we did a video on Finance Bureau
about Lego, you know, the um the the
kids toys that is really popular now.
And no one gave no one watched it.
>> Just just label it label it dubious
speculation and then people watch.
>> But it it's so interesting because it's
like, you know, I think like a lot of us
want to sort of try and find a more
positive spin to put on things, you
know, to look at things that are going
well, but then no one watches them. So,
it's that kind of doom loop, you know,
it's like kind, you know, and and you're
you're in a sort of chicken and egg
situation, you know, what came first,
the you know, the doomerish content or
the people watching the doomerish only
watching the doomerish content, you
know, and it just sort of feeds round
and round. It's um yeah, I mean we're
we're as as audiences I kind of think
we're all our own worst enemies. You
know, we we we want to watch our
confirmation bias or our bias seems to
be more towards um you know, bad news
rather than good news. Maybe it's just a
maybe it's just something hardwired in
us by by evolution. Okay, speaking of uh
speaking of bad news, um crypto,
speaking of bad news,
>> speaking of echo chambers, um crypto has
had a bit of a slow start to October. Um
so what do you gentlemen think we need
to take us higher? Is there anything
that you can, you know, that you can
point to that you think might just sort
of give crypto a bit of a boost? because
as I as I would like to remind you, we
are now over a week into so-called
October and that the up bit of that
seems to have gone slightly AWOL. Um
Rob, is there anything you're sort of
you've got on your horizon as a
potential good news catalyst? Well, just
remember October can be replaced with
Rectober pretty quickly and that's for
>> now. Of course, I'm going to say the the
bearish part and everybody's going to
get mad because I'm a little bit
bearish, but again, I mean, if we're
not going to go over well, fouryear
cycles still could play out and Ben even
talked about it, right? If we see with
with the 10 years, the 20 year, 30-year
uh bonds as they start to go up, if they
continue to go up, I know Scott Asent
just put in like $148 billion or
something like that to buy off, which
great, you know, that'll lower it,
that'll ease the markets. But if if we
see more of these of this war and a
continuation in Iran and we start to see
the price of diesel continue to go up
and fluctuate and go all over the place,
then you're going to see more of a of an
inflation issue. Once we have an
inflation issue, then you're going to
have the Fed come out maybe not for the
next meeting at the end of October, but
in December and say, "Okay, we got to
raise rates again." Then who knows how
many for the next part. And again,
midterms are coming in. I think
everything has to get flushed out right
now. And I know that people are they're
nervous about what it is. And again, if
you if you want to compare rates, I
think on Ben's site on the 10 and three
month and three month, there is an
aversion. And every time we get an
inversion of those yields, we hit a
recession. And that's been going on for
like over a year now, about a year, 18
months or so. So we should be at some
point hit that type of thing. And
everybody's some people are calling for
it. The bond vigilantes think is going
to happen. So I think we have to flush
everybody out and just kind of move
forward. I just want to get through Q4
and the midterms and let's just see who
wins and we can move forward from that.
It's probably going to be the Democrats
in the House, maybe the Senate flips,
and of course that means a lame duck as
far as President Trump and then we'll
ride out these two years.
>> Yeah, let's see. Let's see. Ben, same
question to you. What is there anything
you're sort of looking at to take us
higher in crypto specifically?
>> Um, I mean, usually it's just time that
we need, right, in order to got to flush
you have to flush out all the people
over over a certain length of time. Um,
I mean, I I think that the the thing
next week that people will be watching
is the uh the inflation report, right? I
think that that's going to come out next
week. So,
>> that's probably your next big catalyst
one way or the other. If it if it comes
in really really hot, then
>> that would probably be a really negative
thing for for crypto. Um, just because
it means we're going to have to have
higher higher rates and and whatnot.
if it comes in soft, then perhaps that
could help give it a boost. But I I
think the issue that that crypto has
right now is that um you know the things
there's still so many tailwinds on CPI
in the short term that it's going to be
constantly fighting that, right? Like
inflation is likely going to head higher
in the short term. I'm not necessarily
in the camp that we're going to have
this massive inflationary wave again.
Um, but I I think it could go high
enough just to, you know, kind of stall
stall things out for a little bit. I
mean, this is the, you know, in some
ways we we I talked a little bit about
how it's like 2019, you know, and the
the whole last cycle and and whatnot,
but one of the differences between now
and back then was back then when crypto
was coming down and then and then sort
of settling, they were they were
lowering rates. um whereas this time
they're raising rates. So there actually
is a difference between between now and
and back then they're they're
potentially raising rates. So I I think
monetary policy has has a pretty large
effect on this as well. And and I and
the other thing too as it because you
guys mentioned altcoins. Um the the
thing last cycle that you know caught a
lot of people by surprise was that the
bull market bitcoin outperformed
basically everything and a lot of people
thought that the altcoin market would
eventually catch up and and it didn't.
And and so that that is proof right
there that not every cycle has to have
an alt season associated with it. And I
know I sounded crazy last cycle, you
know, talking about that, but hopefully
like now people can look at that and be
like, "All right, there is some merit to
the idea that restrictive monetary
policy could make it so that alts would
underperform." And if it can happen
once, it could theoretically
happen again. Now, my guess is that it
it it is going to happen again, but it
won't last for as long as it did last
time, right? Because last time it was
the entire cycle. I guess is it it it's
more like uh it's for half the cycle or
something where restrictive policy takes
back over and we see Bitcoin do better
than altcoins. But just something
something to consider. So I think a lot
of it comes down to to monetary policy
um and liquidity. So liquidity is the
biggest one because I think I think
crypto really reacts to that. And I
think the hard thing right now is that
there's not really a reason for the Fed
to print when when the stock market is
just at all-time highs, right? Like week
after week, all-time highs. And you
know, I feel crazy buying index funds
every single month because it, you know,
I keep thinking like, yeah, I mean,
we'll have a correction at some point.
We just keep it keeps going higher. Um,
and you know, I mean, I who knows I mean
it could last for a while. You know, who
knows really how long it'll last before
before that gives up. But I I think you
can't really have much looser monetary
policy until until there's weakness in
the stock market.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's a good point. I I
feel the same with with buying with
buying stocks, with buying index funds,
you know, but people have been talking
about a crash for such a long time now,
you know, especially an AI related
crash. And it's like, yeah, you know,
there there there is a very good chance
that we're going to get one of those.
But like you can just lose you can lose
out on so much, can't you? By just being
sidelined, you know, waiting for that.
And and you know, it it'll come, but who
knows? I mean, it could the whole thing
could keep chugging along for quite a
while.
>> Yeah. I mean, I've been buying index
funds monthly for like a decade now. And
>> I mean, they'd have to drop a lot to get
back to where they were in like 2022,
2023. I mean, I don't like that'd be a
really really bad drop for for them to
get that low. So, I think as an
investor, right, I think as an investor,
everyone just has to recognize at some
point that no matter what they do, they
will be involved in, you know, drops in
the stock market at at some point,
right? But there's, as the famous saying
is as is there's more money lost in
betting on stock market crashes than the
actual stock market crashes themselves.
And I think that I think that all of us
would like to believe that we can avoid
that. But the reality is is like, you
know, if you do avoid it, you probably
also missed out on a lot of the gains
that would have had occurred, you know,
sort of preceding it, right? Constantly
betting on it on it to drop. So that's
why I don't even try to time the stock
market. I mean, I I I do try to time the
uh the Bitcoin market sometimes with
mixed mixed success, but uh with the
stock market, I don't even try I don't
even try to time it.
Yeah. Yeah. Rob, are you the same? Are
you just because I know you I know
you're a big advocate of DCA in crypto.
Are you basically the same with stocks
as well?
>> Yeah. Well, I use this I use this
website uh it's called ITC and uh I get
these risk levels and I can do that for
stocks as well which is pretty nice, you
know, as far as like with Tesla and
Google, the big ones, Cloudflare and uh
I like those things and it's worked out
pretty well. But I I will just just to
piggyback on what what Ben said about,
you know, recessions and, you know,
these things could happen as if you just
throw this little graphic. Uh this is
where all the money's made and if we do
get a recession, I know it's it's it's a
horrible rword, but they average out 10
months. And of course, once you're in a
recession, it's a little bit too late
because they're they're calling it late.
And then once you're out of recession,
they don't get they don't usually get
that right. So you could see a much
smaller time frame. And if you could
just weather the storm like you've done
like you watch in the video every four
years in these in these cycles, you're
going to be just fine. And actually, I
think some people might welcome some big
dips and pullbacks. So
>> yeah, time in the market beats timing
the market as I think the old cliche
goes. Uh, great. Thank you for that
gent. One more question before I let you
go to to frolic and live your lives. Um
there's a lot of debate at the moment
over how useful AI really is. Um some
people are saying uh that they're saving
a you know hours every single day by
getting uh agents to handle you know
mundane tasks things like booking them
restaurants or flights or like you know
handling their emails etc. Um while
you've got other people out there saying
well what's all the fuss about? I I
don't mind booking my own flights. Why
would I get AI to do it? So, um, I'm
just curious as to where both of you
guys stand on this. Have you, because I
know you both use AI, you know, we've
talked about that a lot on this on this
show before, but are you kind of letting
it, you know, are you letting it into
your inbox? Are you sort of giving it,
you know, access to your computer, or
are you just kind of using an an LLM
interface like like Claude or or Chat
GBT or whatever it is to sort of answer
questions and and and do whatever. Um,
Rob, can I I can I go to you first on
this one?
>> The easy answer is you shouldn't let AI
do anything because it can destroy
everything within your ecosystem. But I
remember the same thing that was said
about online purchases. Remember that
>> you can't use your debit card because
everything's going to get stolen and
you're going to get wasted. And then of
course people like, well, what's this
thing called Amazon? Wow, I can get this
delivered. How fast? That's great. And
everything now you buy it on on the
internet and that's pretty much how it
goes. But as far as like like uh AI, I
use it for specific things. I don't give
it access to my bank or trading
accounts. U I just don't believe that
bigger spectrum except with with with it
trust, but that's that's within their
their ecosystem. But for me, I use it
for, you know, the basics like for the
short-term, medium-term rentals, for
doing these videos, for doing taxes and
putting everything together for my CPA
to make sure it actually works to make
sure that the different sites that I
have, I have over I have eight websites
that I actually pay the best price and
just offload those. And I did this and
shameless plug, guy, if you could.
>> Oh, yes, of course.
>> Thank you. There's a there's this second
channel called Dne. If you just look for
Dane GoDaddy, you'll find it. And this
is where I've eliminated thousands of
dollars every year just by using
Cloudflare, just by using AWS, just by
using Google and their their
substandards to actually pull everything
over. And the thing was people would
say, well, Rob, if you do that, who's
your developer? How how do you make sure
that things don't don't break and
everything else? That's what Claude's
for. And then also those videos, if you
watch and see the the graphics come in,
I don't do any of that. I just record
myself. I tell Claude, "Now do the
graphics and it doesn't really ask me
that much because I I use Cloud for a
lot of things and it just does it and
then off I go." I just don't allow it to
have access to my uh bank accounts,
credit cards, and things like that. They
want if it wants to see a statement and
to to verify that a transaction was
good, I will up I will show a CSV or a
PDF. So, that's how I've done things.
>> Yeah. Interesting. That view that video
had 115k views in four days. That's
That's
>> That's almost like That's almost like
one Ben Cowan video. That's crazy.
>> Almost almost as popular as dubious
speculation.
>> Um well, congrat congratulations on your
on your new channel, Rob. So, I urge
everyone to subscribe to that. So,
that's Dne D A N.
>> D. And I just I I don't compare like
different models and and and and the
theoreticals. I just show you what I do
to make my life a hell of a lot easier
and save money.
>> Fantastic. Fantastic. Check it out,
folks. Ben, same question to you. At
what what level what extent are you
letting AI into your life? I mean, I
know you're a busy man. You've got a big
family. You know, you're you're you're
organizing the ITC conference uh in
Miami next month, November. Get your
tickets. Um so presumably you you've
just delegated every single mundane task
out there to AI, right?
Um, yeah. I mean, AI, it gets my kids
up, takes them to school, you know,
everything else. No. Um,
no. I mean, I I I I use it. I I it I
doesn't have access to like my entire
everything, right? Like, but I mean,
>> I know a lot of people that that do that
and
it's been great, right? I mean because
we have we've got a lot of uh like for
for the ITC platform for instance like
you know AI has a lot of access to that
so that we can build that make it make
it even better. Um
I use it you know I use it for helping
to plan a lot of things. I just went to
New Zealand. Uh, I was speaking at at
TechSummit 2026 in New Zealand and while
I was in New Zealand, it was basically
my travel agent, you know, I mean, I
would just I just basically say like,
you know, these are the things my wife
and I like to do and we're going to be
here for 10 days, you know, come up with
an itinerary for us and, you know, it
would do that and then, you know, I have
to go in and tweak it and be like, well,
I don't really want to do that. Uh, but
it was great. I mean, I use it for a lot
of stuff and I also I also use it for
making um charts, like you know, sort of
figuring out like new things to look at,
new ways to look at the market, that
kind of stuff. So, I I I use it a lot. I
don't use it as much as some people, but
I I still meet a lot of people when I
talk about like AI and I show them what
it can do, like they're still surpris
they have no idea that this and I know
that sounds crazy to us because it's
like, well, you use it, you know, how
could you not know about it? But there
are a lot of people that don't really
know that much about it yet. Um, which
means I mean there's probably
opportunities there, you know, to to I
mean because that's the thing is a lot
of times people think that AI will take
everyone's jobs but and while they while
it will take some jobs, I I said this
before I think AI I think people who
know how to use AI will be the ones
taking jobs. And I think that's kind of
like the the thing that So I think if
people are if if they have some free
time, I think it'd be useful to go learn
how to use this stuff. I think it'd be
worthwhile.
>> Yeah.
>> Then I think the next uh model of Claude
is supposed to be much better at picking
the kids up from school
>> and and cooking them. So
>> just wait for that. Just make sure you
just make sure you buy enough credits
and you'll be fine. Yeah, I think that
we have to the probably the next
business cycle after this one will be
the the robotics one maybe.
>> Yeah,
>> where where we're incorporating AI into
robotics. That'd be that that would be
kind of cool. I mean, that'd be really
cool, honestly.
>> Yeah.
>> Kind of scary.
>> Kind of scary. We're living in the uh
the Terminator future, right? But it
it'd be pretty cool.
>> Four years time, it would just be three
Terminators that usually imagine the
doomerism in that business cycle.
>> Oh.
Yes. You ain't seen nothing yet.
>> We haven't seen nothing.
>> I love it. I love it. Um Yeah. No, I
that's that's that's really interesting.
And uh and thanks for those thanks for
those answers, gentlemen, because I was
um I was following um I don't know uh
you guys know Nick Carter from Castle
Island Ventures.
>> Yeah. um you know big crypto VC very
smart guy and I follow him on Twitter
but he posted some he was posting quite
a lot of stuff about what he you know
gets his AI to do and I mean it's a huge
long list and um there was quite a lot
of push back from you know some of it
quite sort of aggressive being like oh
you crypto guys you just like you know
you're just idiots getting your AI to do
everything blah blah blah and Nick was
sort of pushing back quite a lot you
know and and and sort of replying to
these people and I just thought is kind,
you know, I kind of enjoyed the irony of
it. You know, he's saved so much time by
getting AI to do all this stuff for him.
Yeah.
>> And how's he spending it? By arguing
about by arguing with people about it.
It's just like
>> just dude, go and learn how to play the
piano or, you know, learn another
language or something like that. So,
you've saved all this time. Like, use it
wisely for God's sake. Um,
>> okay. We will leave it there. Thank you
very much, Ben. Thank you very much,
Rob. Um, we will be back next week, Guy,
Ben, uh, Rob. So, on Ben's channel next
week.
>> Yeah,
>> you could you could really hear the cogs
worring there, couldn't you? Um, so, uh,
we will see you all then. Uh, have a
wonderful week, everyone, and, uh, back
with you soon. Thanks very much.
>> See you guys, everybody.
>> See you.